The idea is our smart.
Avatar is a stateful component so it can hold some state
it can it can be responsible for counting the API and we'll
do that in its lifecycle hooks, right?
So the with after URL should return a smart Avatar itself.
In this case.
We use objects in tanks.
The first thing we do is instead of accepting source as a
prop. We accept username as a prom.
Right and the other thing is it should be rendering.
Remember to use the proper function syntax.
Obviously, it should be just returning the Avatar component
internally because ultimately this is what we're trying to
do. The interesting thing is we want to pass additional data.
One to pass props to Avatar.
We want to pass.
It's the source prompts.
The question is, how do we find out what the source is?
Right and let's just say So let's just say we have some.
local state anxiety this component, which is URL And by default
when we first load this component, we only have the username.
We don't have the URL yet.
And the requirement says we should wait.
It's here Hey, where's the requirement?
Okay.
It's here.
It says before the API Returns.
The higher-order component should be passing a placeholder
URL to the inner component.
So we just copy that and use that as the default value for
our URL here, right and we'll just whatever we're just passing
it in.
So now we first we've created a smart Avatar component not
so smart.
It always just renders in Avatar with a placeholder image
and now we need to figure out how to find out where the real
URL is.
So let's do that in a lifecycle hook.
So when the component is created we're going to call this
API. We're going to fetch URL.
And because it's Express the username, we're just right we
caught it with the username and it accepts a callback which
gives you the URL that we need.
in inside that call back or just set our URL to the correct
URL all right, so does this make sense?
So essentially we're maintaining an intermediate immediate
piece of state and this this state is the URL and it starts
with a placeholder and it's changed after we've fetched the
the desired URL from the API and all we're doing is just
passing it down to the inner Avatar component.
The good thing is we've extracted the piece of functionality
very cleanly out of the inner outer component into this thing.
And I believe this should work.
So it's better to just actually open it they are so this
is the effect so it shows the placeholder then turns into
that. So imagine you can do something like a blurring effect
or initially showing some other things you can do a lot of
fancy stuff in here, but the good thing is you can encapsulate
all of that anxiety this higher order component.
It doesn't leak anywhere else.
So we're just really nice.
So one small thing that we might want to think about is that
it's this component currently is pretty unoptimized in the
sense. It always hits the API whenever it's created, you
know, but we
actually create something like a cash here that cash is the
user name and URL pairs so that we don't need to actually
hit the you hit the API all the time, you know, you can have
a cashier with a user name and URL payers and inside our
Data here.
We can directly start with a cached hit if it exists and
we check again here.
If it's already a cache hit we don't even need to call the
API at all.
So you can do a lot of things optimizations fancy functionalities
anxiety here, but it doesn't affect the usage to the parent
component at all.
No matter what you do inside that component this parent component
use it stays the same this inner.
Opponents the Avatar component stayed the same.
They don't need to change right you can do all the work inside
your inner this higher order component, but you are not affecting
your parent your child.
So this is good because it shows that it has is it's a good
encapsulation means the only interface we're using to talk
between the parent and the child is vir props.
Because the the way we communicate is so constrained this
make ensures that changing the inner implementation of this
enhancer doesn't affect other pieces Parts in your codes.
This is critical.
If you have a large team large project and you want to make
sure when you are changing things, you're not stepping on
other people's toes and not accidentally breaking other things
and the trick to that is make sure this piece of codes by
Contracts with other parts of the code base is minimal.
In this case.
The only thing that it's connecting to other pieces in your
code are the incoming props and outgoing props.
So this is great because this is a very very clear constraint.
It's very minimal.
It gives you very little chance of breaking other people's
things in your render function there.
You're referencing Avatar.
Should you be actually referencing the inner components?
Yes.
That's a that's a mistake here.
Yep.
So yeah, this makes this with Avatar you are a more generic.
So any inner component that takes a URL props can be used
with this with Avatar URL thing and it can be more generic.
For example, you can take something like you can even pass
the fetch URL function here, right?
So instead of hard-coded to always be fetching avatars, you
can on the Fly customize what you're actually fetch.
It takes the username.
You can fetch the Avatar you can fetch other information
about the user but you're using the same interface to enhance
inner components and this increases the reusability for this
enhancer as well.
What are the difference between created amounted hooks for
fetching data?
To be honest, the difference is is minimal.
The main difference is that mounted is called after the rendering
happens and the dump actual Dom nodes are created.
So technically created will be called earlier than your the
mounted if your component takes, you know a long time to
render then create.
It might be called even earlier than mounted and it's good.
To send the request out beforehand because the request needs
to go through the internet and there's latency.
So the latency can overlap with the time it takes to render
a component.
So that's the main thing there was a there was an early question
about slots.
It's I think it's actually easier to read the docs about
slots, but slots API was actually derived from the same standard
from w3c.
And so in web components, there's the slot mechanism and
Views implementation Loosely follows that the spec but we
kind of enhance it in a few ways and most importantly view
slot mechanism Works in rent.
As to so if you use a function that uses rendered functions,
I use a component that uses random functions like this so
you can do slots equals Foo.
And the way to access this slot inside a random function
is by doing this dollar slots Foo.
This will give you an array of virtual nodes.
That falls into the slot.
Because this you can have multiple things that falls into
the same slot.
So you get have an array and if you don't give it any slot
name. Then all unnamed ones will be inside this daughter
slots the default.
This is also an array so you can like pass them directly
as children.
to this essentially you're passing on the slot content into
this inner component even better.
Well, yeah, this is a typical use case.
Another thing another trick that we can talk about is.
Inheriting the outer attributes.
So we have this higher order components like here.
If you do something like ID equals Foo, unfortunately, it
won't be passed down to the inner component because we didn't
explicitly list it but this ID will in fact be collected
inside an attribute card a property called at this dollar
attrs. This is a new feature in two point four, which means
you can pass it down like this.
So this way you're relaying all the additional attributes
down to the inner component.
So this ID will in fact now be rendered on the internal Avatar.
But the default behavior is only explicitly listed props
will be passed down.
This also means in created hook you cannot access Domino's.
That's correct.
So the created hook only Mount Hood guarantees.
The Dom has been created in created hook.
It means instance is created on the dock on the website.
There is a documentation.
life cycle diagram As you can see when the create a hook
is called we have initialized events lifecycle injections
and reactivity.
These are instance specific.
They don't have anything to do with the Dom or rendering
or anything.
Real rendering only happens after create a hook has been
called and there could be on the fire compliation and then
virtual Dom rendering and eventually when the actual Dom
has been created.
That's when mounted will be called.
So now the component is considered to being mounted States.
Off-topic question in new router could import food would
be changed to something like lazy and ports to get a slightly
simpler syntax.
Not really.
So the question is really about a sink components and code
splitting together.
I think this currency in Texas is already simple enough.
Introducing so the more important thing is the import syntax
Dynamic import is a speck right arrow function is part of
JavaScript Dynamic important part of JavaScript.
We're just using these standard language features for acing
components and code splitting which in my opinion is better
than having to have a custom lazy import function, which
is not part of the standard in my you know, Essentially,
we're having a our own API instead of using standard language
features.